A register of the Aleksandr Il'ich Ginzburg Papers, 1921-2007
Hoover Institution Archives
- Sound and video recordings, 1970s-1990s; undated; 10 boxes and three folders (Box 17-27; 11: 9-11;)
  - Sound recordings, 1970s-1990s. (Box 20-26)
    - Brodsky, Joseph. 4 compact sound cassettes Dolina, Veronika, with IUliĬ Kim, SergeĬ Nikitin, and Tat'iana Nikitina. 6 compact sound cassettes Dolina, Veronika, with SergeĬ Nikitin and Tat'iana Nikitina. 1 compact sound cassette Dolina, Veronika. 15 compact sound cassettes Dudko, Father DmitriĬ, reading his translation of Aesop's fables. 1 compact sound cassette Galich, Aleksandr. 16 compact sound cassettes (Box 21)
    - Galich, Aleksandr. 2 compact sound cassettes Genkin, Aleksandr, with Ada IAkusheva and Aleksandr Dulov. 1 compact sound cassette Gershtein, Larisa. 1 compact sound cassette Grebenshchikov, Boris. 1 compact sound cassette IAkubovich, Elena. 2 compact sound cassettes Khodorovich, SergeĬ, Pesni nevoli. 1 compact sound cassette Khvostenko, AlekseĬ. 4 compact sound cassettes Kim, IUliĬ. 32 compact sound cassettes (Box 22)
    - Kim, IUliĬ. 17 compact sound cassettes Kim, IUliĬ, with Mikhail ZhvanetskiĬ. 1 compact sound cassette Kim, IUliĬ, interview by Arina Ginzburg. 1 compact sound cassette Kliachkin, EvgeniĬ. 1 compact sound cassette Kukin, IUriĬ. 3 compact sound cassettes Kul'turnyĬ bul'on. 1 compact sound cassette Luferov, Viktor. 1 compact sound cassette Matveeva, Novella. 3 compact sound cassettes Nikitin, SergeĬ, and Tat'iana Nikitina. 3 compact sound cassettes Okudzhava, Bulat, celebration of his 60th birthday. 2 compact sound cassettes Okudzhava, Bulat. 8 compact sound cassettes (Box 23)
    - Okudzhava, Bulat. 30 compact sound cassettes Putilin, Aleksandr. 2 compact sound cassettes Ratushinskaia, Irina, program in her honor. 2 compact sound cassettes Rozenbaum, Aleksandr. 1 compact sound cassette Sakharov, AndreĬ, press-conference at his home. 1 compact sound cassette Saltykov, SergeĬ. 1 compact sound cassette Skorov, ValeriĬ. 6 compact sound cassettes (Box 24)
    - Skorov, ValeriĬ. 3 compact sound cassettes Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr, interviews, speeches, and his reading of short stories and of Odin den' Ivana Denisovicha. 13 compact sound cassettes Starchik, Petr. 5 compact sound cassettes Tarakanov, IUriĬ. 2 compact sound cassettes VertinskiĬ, Aleksandr. 1 compact sound cassette Vizbor, IUriĬ. 3 compact sound cassettes Vladimirskaia, Zhanna, with AlekseĬ Kovalev. 2 compact sound cassettes Vysotsky, Vladimir. 13 compact sound cassettes (Box 25)
    - Vysotsky, Vladimir. 37 compact sound cassettes Vysotsky, Vladimir, concert in his memory. 2 compact sound cassettes Vysotsky, Vladimir, and Aleksandr Dol'skiĬ. 1 compact sound cassette ZhvanetskiĬ, Mikhail. 3 compact sound cassettes (Box 26)
  - Video recordings, 1979-2002. (Box 27)
    Includes 18 videotape cassettes (VHS) with Ginzburg's lectures, television programs, documentaries, and interviews.
    - Ginzburg, interview by CBS correspondent at the Saint Vladimir seminary, New York, ca 1980 (Tape 27: 1)
    - International Sakharov hearings on human rights, New York, 1979 (Tape 27: 2)
    - World Affairs Council, Loma-Linda University, Southern California, November 1979. (Tape 27: 3)
      Lecture and discussion
    - Lectures, fall of 1980 (Tape 27: 4)
    - Farleigh Dickinson University, 26 February 1985. (Tape 27: 5)
      Lecture
    - French television program with Ginzburg in memory of AnatoliĬ Marchenko, 29 December 1986 (Tape 27: 6)
    - "Dissidenty," French television program, undated. (Tape 27: 7)
    - "Trizhdy zek," Russian television program, 4 April, 16 June, and 29 August 1992, "Sintaksis Aleksandra Ginzburga," Sovershenno sekretno, Russian television program, 1993, 1992-1993 (Tape 27: 8-10)
    - Deti arkhipelaga, undated (Tape 27: 11)
    - IUliĬ Kim, musical; VitaliĬ Rubin benefit, undated (Tape 27: 12)
    - Ginzburg, interview regarding Russkaia mysl', undated. (Tape 27: 13)
    - Duel' Vadima Delone, documentary, ca 1999 (Tape 27: 14)
    - "ParizhskiĬ zhurnal 'Russkaia mysl',' with Arina Ginzburg and Irina IlovaIUliĬskaia-Alberti, 2001 (Tape 27: 15)
    - "Chelovek legendy,", undated. (Tape 27: 16)
      Documentary about Aleksandr Ginzburg
    - "Les témoins du Goulag," French program, 29 November 2002 (Tape 27: 17)
    - Meeting in memory of Aleksandr Ginzburg, 21 November 2002. (Tape 17: 18)
      Memorial Society, Moscow
- Memorabilia, 1970s-2002; 1 box (Box 26)
  Playing card set, ephemera, ex-libris bookplate set, and U.S. one-dollar bill signed by G. William Miller, U.S. Secretary of the Treasury,
  - Elect playing cards set picturing Russian politicians, 1990s (Folder 28: 1)
  - Ephemera relating to cultural events in Paris (concerts, exhibitions, and others), 1978-2002 (Folder 28: 2)
  - Ex libris bookplates set, presumably by Filip Makhonin, 1970s (Folder 28: 3)
  - U.S. one-dollar bill signed by G. William Miller, U.S. Secretary of the Treasury, ca 1980 (Folder 28: 4)
- Oversize material, 1966-2002; undated; 1 box (Box 29-30)
  Soviet prison rules, color print, award certificates, advertising materials, newspapers, and clippings.
  Box 29 arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - Awards, 1979-1980; undated (Box 29)
    - American Federation of Teachers, undated. (Item 29)
    - Coalition for a Democratic Majority, Friend of Freedom award, Washington, D.C., 19 June 1979 (Item 29)
    - The Cuban Nation in Exile plaque, 27 November 1979 (Item 29)
    - Holy Cross College honorary diploma, Massachusetts, 1979 (Item 29)
    - Key for the City of New Jersey, 9 April 1980 (Item 29)
    - Sheriff of Hudson County, New Jersey, Distinguished Service Award, 9 April 1980 (Item 29)
    - Ross McWhirter Foundation plaque, 30 April 1980 (Item 29)
    - New York Senate resolution #739, proclaiming June 1980 a "Month of Conscience" in remembrance of Soviet citizens denied the right to emigrate, 5 June 1980 (Item 29)
  - Color print portraying mother [Arina Ginzburg] and her two sons being spied on by the KGB, Koktebel', 1978 (Item 29)
  - Soviet prison rules, Osnovnye prava i obiazannosti zakliuchennykh i mery pooshchreniia i nakazaniia primeniaemye k nim, undated. (Item 29)
  - Newspapers and newspaper clippings, 1966-2002. (Folder 30: 1-10)
    The content is described in their corresponding series